Guide to the Society of the Emeriti records, 1988-1997 RG0032
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Society of the Emeriti records
1988-1997
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Society of the Emeriti
RG0032
1 Linear Feet
Collection includes updates from John Francis Latimer, biographies (including Thelma Hunt and George Nordlinger), correspondence and other items from the files of William Turner, as well as recordings and transcripts of Clyde Lindley and George Steiner speaking about their careers upon induction.
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open for us.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from the President of the Society of the Emeriti.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Society of the Emeriti began in February 1978. After Dr. Lloyd Elliott entertained two groups of emeriti and their wives the idea was born to form a permanent emeriti group that would meet once a month for lunch, education and conversation. Dr. John Latimer was principle mover in forming the group. To be a member of SOTE, as it was called, one had to be an emeritus of the university or have 25 years of service to the university. The organization still meets once a month for lunch.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include updates from John Francis Latimer, biographies (including Thelma Hunt and George Nordlinger), correspondence and other items from the files of William Turner, and tape recordings and transcripts of Clyde Lindley and George Steiner speaking about their careers upon induction. The collection covers the years 1991 to 1996.
Collection Organization
Organized into three series: Updates, Biographies and correspondence, and Recordings and transcripts of meetings.
Biography; Washington (D.C.); Meetings; Elliott, Lloyd H.; George Washington University; Latimer, John Francis; Hunt, Thelma; Nordlinger, George
- Updates, RG0032 Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains updates provided by John Francis Latimer.
  - Updates from John Latimer, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
- Biographies and correspondence, 1989-1996; RG0032 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains biographies, newsletters, vitaes, notices, and membership records. The material covers the years 1991-96. The subjects of the biographies include Thelma Hunt and George Nordlinger and correspondence from the files of William Turner.
  - GWU Club Society of the Emeriti Biographies, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notices of Society of Emeriti luncheon meetings, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Thelma Hunt, Dr. George Nordlinger, Burney Jarman, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vitae of Deans, Unviersity officials used for intros at Society of the Emeriti meetings, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni eligible for membership in Society of Emeriti, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Misc. newsletters, correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mailings and member directories, 1989-2005; Series 2 (Box SHARED 2)
- Recordings and transcripts of meetings, 1995; Series 3; 0.25 Linear Feet 1 slim document box
  Scope and Contents
  Consists of tape recordings and transcripts of portions of meetings of the Society at which George Steiner and Clyde Lindley spoke about thier careers and were inducted.
  - George Steiner speaking about his experiences at George Washington University at meeting of the Society of the Emeriti at which he was elected to its membership, 1995 March; 1 Cassettes; 1 folder(s) (Box 2, Cassette 1)
  - Clyde Lindley speaking about his experiences at George Washington University and his research on aging at meeting of the Society of the Emeriti at which he was elected to its membership, 1995 May; Series 1 Subseries 1; 1 Cassettes; 1 folder(s) (Box 2, Cassette 2)